安巴西电影公司出品
Ladies and gentlemen, we're about to begin our descent into Los Angeles.
The sound you just heard is the landing gear locking into place.
Los angeles weather is clear. The temperature is 72.
We expect to make our 4-hour and 18-minute flight on schedule.
We have enjoyed having you on board
and look forward to seeing you again in the near future.
Please hold handrail and stand to the right
if you wish to pass, please do so on the left.
监制：麦克.尼科斯 罗伦斯.特尔曼
片名：毕业生
主演：安妮.班克富特 德斯汀.荷夫曼
You attention, please. Parking in the area is limited to three minutes only.
Please do not leave your car unattended.
导演：麦克.尼科斯
Hey, what's the matter?
The guests are all downstairs, Ben, waiting to see you.
Look, dad, could you explain that I have to be alone for a while?
These are all our good friends, Ben.
Most of them have known you since well, practically since you were born.
What is it, Ben?
I'm just...
worried?
Well...
about what?
I guess about my future.
What about it?
I don't know.
I want it to be...
to be what?
Different.
- Is anything wrong? - No, no.
- We're just on our way downstairs. - The Carlsons are here.
They are? Well, come on.
They came all the way from Tarzana.
Come on, let's get cracking.
It's a wonderful thing to have so many devoted friends.
Hey, there's the award-winning scholar!
- We're all very proud of you, Ben. - Thank you, Mrs. Carlsons.
Is that the new car out there? That little red wop job?
That's Ben's graduation present.
You won't have much trouble picking up in that, will you?
Sir?
The girls, the chicks, the teenyboppers.
I think Ben's gotten beyond the teenybopper stage, haven't you, Ben?
Yes, ma'am.
Excuse me. I' d like to check something on the car for a minute.
His father bought him an alfa romeo.
Hey, here's the track star.
- How are you, track star? - Just fine, Mr. Loomis.
I want to get a drink, then I want to hear all about
that thing that you won, that hopperman award.
- Halpingham. - Halpingham. Right.
You wait right here.
Ben!
We're all so proud of you.
Proud, proud, proud...
What are you going to do now?
I was going to go upstairs for a minute.
I meant with your future.
- Your life. - Well, that's a little hard to say.
- Ben. - Excuse me.
Mr. Mcguire.
Ben.
Come with me a minute. I want to talk to you.
Excuse us, Joanne.
- Of course. - Thanks. Thank you
Congratulations!
Llook at him, and I can't believe it.
I just want to say one word to you.
Just one word.
Yes, sir.
- Are you listening? - Yes, I am.
Plastics.
Exactly how do you mean?
There's a great future in plastics.
Think about it.
- Will you think about it? - Yes, I will.
Shh! Enough said. That's a deal
Here he is now. Here's Ben.
Excuse me just a minute.
Listen, everybody, I want you all to be quiet.
I've got ben's college yearbook here,
and I just want to read you some of the wonderful things about Ben.
Be quiet, please!
Captain of the cross-country team, head of the debating club,
associate editor of the college newspaper in his junior year,
managing editor in his senior...
Oh, I guess this isn't the bathroom, is it?
It's, uh, down the hall.
- How are you, Benjamin? - Fine, thank you, Mrs. Robinson.
The bathroom's down at the end of the hall.
Such a pleasant room.
Look, uh... Mrs. Robinson, I don't mean to be rude, but...
- I' m awfully... - Is there an ashtray in here?
No.
Oh, yes, I forgot the track star doesn't smoke.
Is it a girl
Is what a girl
Whatever it is that's upsetting you.
Oh, no, I' m just, uh... sort of disturbed about things.
- In general - That's right.
Well... congratulations.
Thank you.
Oh, Benjamin.
- I want to ask you something. - What?
- Will you take me home? - What?
My husband took the car. Will you drive me home?
Here, you take it.
You know how to work a foreign shift?
- You don't? - No
Let's go.
- Thank you. - Right.
Will you come in, please?
What?
I'd like you to come in till I get the lights on.
What for?
Because I don't feel safe till I get the lights on.
Would you mind walking ahead of me to the sun porch?
I feel funny about coming into a dark house.
But it's light in there.
Please.
What do you drink? Bourbon?
Look, Mrs. Robinson, I drove you home, I was glad to do it.
But I have some things on my mind. Can you understand that?
- Yes. - All right.
What do you drink?
Benjamin, I' m sorry to be this way,
but I don't want to be left alone in this house.
Why not?
Please wait till my husband gets home.
When is he coming back?
I don't know.
- Drink? - No.
Are you always this much afraid of being alone?
Yes.
Well, why can't you just lock the doors and go to bed?
I'm very neurotic.
May I ask you a question?
What do you think of me?
What do you mean?
You've known me nearly all your life. You must've formed some opinion of me.
Well, I always thought that you were a very nice person.
Did you know I was an alcoholic?
What?
Did you know that?
Look, I think I should be going.
Sit down, Benjamin.
Mrs. Robinson, if you don't mind my saying so,
this conversation is getting a little strange.
Now, I' m sure Mr. Robinson will be here any minute...
- No. - What?
My husband will be back quite late.
He should be gone for several hours.
- Oh, my god. - Pardon?
Oh, no, Mrs. Robinson. Oh, no.
What's wrong?
Mrs. Robinson, you didn't... I mean, you didn't expect...
What?
I mean, you didn't really think I'd do something like that.
Like what?
- What do you think? - Well, I don't know.
For god's sake,
Mrs. Robinson. Here we are. You got me into your house,
you give me a drink, you put on music,
now you start opening up your personal life to me
and telling me your husband won't be home for hours.
So?
Mrs. Robinson, you're trying to seduce me.
Aren't you?
Well, no, I hadn't thought of it.
I feel very flattered.
Will you forgive me for what I just said?
It's all right.
It's not all right. It 's the worst thing I ever said to anyone.
Sit down.
Please forgive me, because I like you.
I don't think of you that way, but I' m mixed up.
It's all right. Finish your drink.
Mrs. Robinson, it makes me sick that I said that to you.
We'll forget it right now. Finish your drink.
What is wrong with me?
Have you ever seen Elaine's portrait?
Wha... her portrait?
- Yes. - No.
We had it done last christmas. Would you like to see it?
Very much.
It's here in Elaine's room.
Elaine certainly is an attractive girl, isn't she?
I don't remember her as having brown eyes.
- Benjamin. - Yes.
Will you come over here a minute?
- Over there? - Mm Hmm.
Sure.
Will you unzip my dress?
I think I' II go to bed.
Oh, well, good night.
Won't you unzip my dress?
I'd rather not, Mrs. Robinson.
If you still think I'm trying to seduce you...
No, I don't, but I just feel a little funny.
Benjamin, you've known me all your life.
- I know that, but I' m... - Come on, it's hard for me to reach.
- Thank you. - Right.
What are you so scared of?
I'm not scared, Mrs. Robinson.
Then why do you keep running away?
Because you're going to bed. I don't think I should be up here.
Haven't you seen anybody in a slip before?
Yes, I have, but I just...
Look, what if Mr. Robinson walked in right now?
What if he did?
It would look pretty funny, wouldn't it?
Don't you think he'd trust us together?
Of course, he does,
but he might get the wrong idea. Anyone might.
I don't see why. I' m twice as old as you. How could anyone think...
They would, don't you see?
Benjamin, I am not trying to seduce you.
I know that, but please, Mrs. Robinson, this is diffic...
Would you like me to seduce you?
What?
Is that what you're trying to tell me?
I'm going home now.
I apologize for what I said.
I hope you can forget it, but I' m going home right now.
- Benjamin. - Yes?
Will you bring up my purse before you go?
I have to go now. I'm sorry.
I really don't want to put this on again. Won't you bring it up?
- Where is it? - On the table in the hall.
- Mrs. Robinson? - I' m in the bathroom.
Well, here's the purse.
Could you bring it up?
Well, I' II hand it to you. Come to the railing, and I' II hand it up.
Benjamin, I' m getting pretty tired of all the suspicion.
Now, if you won't do me a simple favor, I don't know what.
I'm putting it on the top step.
For god's sake, Benjamin, will you stop acting this way and bring me the purse?
I'm putting it here by the door.
- Will you bring it in to me? - I' d rather not.
All right. Put it in Elaine's room where we were.
Right.
Oh, god.
Oh, let me out.
- Don't be nervous. - Get away from that door.
- I want to say something first. - Jesus christ.
Benjamin, I want you to know that I' m available to you,
and if you won't sleep with me this time...
- Oh, my christ. - Lf you won't sleep with me this time,
I want you to know you can call me up anytime,
and we'll make some kind of an arrangement.
- Do you understand what I' m saying? - Let me out.
- Benjamin, do you understand? - Yes, yes, let me out.
I find you very attractive.
- And tell me what... - Oh, Jesus, that's him!
- Is that Ben's car in front? - Yes, sir.
I drove Mrs. Robinson home.
She wanted me to drive her home, so I drove her home.
Swell. I appreciate it.
She's upstairs. She wanted me to wait down here till you got home.
Standing guard over the old castle, are you?
Yes, sir.
Hey, congratulations.
Thank you.
- Looks like you need a refill. - No, I' ve got to go.
Is anything wrong?
You look a little shaken up.
Oh, no, I' m just a little worried about my future.
I'm a little upset about my future.
Come on, let's have a nightcap together.
Scotch?
Bourbon.
Ben...
How old are you now?
20. I'll be 21 next week.
That's a hell of a good age to be.
Thank you.
Thank you very much, sir.
I, uh... I wish I was that age again.
- Because, ben... - Sir?
You'll never be young again.
I know.
Ben, can I say something to you?
What?
Uh, how long have we known each other now?
How long have you and I known each other?
How long have your dad and I been partners?
Quite a while.
- I watched you grow up, Ben. - Yes, sir.
In many ways, I feel as though you were my own son.
Thank you.
So I hope you won't mind my giving you a friendly piece of advice.
I'd like to hear it.
Ben...
I think...
I think you ought to be taking it...
a little easier right now than you seem to be.
Sow a few wild oats. Take things as they come.
Have a good time with the girls and so forth.
Don't get up.
I, uh... I was just telling...
Ben here that he ought to sow a few wild oats,
have a good time while he can. You think that's sound advice?
Yes, I do.
I've got to go.
You have yourself a few flings this summer.
I bet you're quite a ladies' man.
- Oh, no. - What?
You look to me like the kind of guy who has to fight them off.
Doesn't he look to you like the kind of guy who has to fight them off?
Yes, he does.
Oh, say, um... Elaine gets down from berkeley on saturday.
- Oh, yes. - I want you give her a call.
I will.
Benjamin.
- Benjamin? - Yes.
Thank you for taking me home.
I'll see you soon, I hope.
Ladies and gentlemen, your attention, please.
Uh, for this afternoon's feature attraction...
Hey, over there!
Yes, I mean you.
Your attention, please.
Are you ready in there, feature attraction?
Could I speak to you for a second, dad?
Listen, I' m going to ask for a big round of applause
to bring this boy out here, all right?
No, wait a minute. Let me amend that.
To bring this young man out here,
because today he is 21 years old.
Yeah! Let's go! Our food's cold.
Oh, now just hang on a minute, I've got a few words to say.
You always do.
Ho ho ho! Look who's talking.
Dad, can we just talk about this for a second?
I can't hold them much longer, Ben. You better get out here.
I'd like to discuss this.
This boy... I' m sorry, this young man,
is soon to continue his education as a frank halpingham award scholar,
but before he does...
before he does...
You're disappointing them, Ben. You're disappointing them!
- Dad, can you listen? - I' II give you 10 seconds.
He is going to give us a practical demonstration of what...
I feel safe in saying is a pretty exciting birthday present.
And it better work, or I' m out over 200 bucks.
Ok, then, let's hear it now for Benjamin Braddock!
Yay!
Come out, Benjy! Come on, Benjy!
Let's hear it now! Thatta boy!
Well, folks, this remarkable young man is going to perform for you
some spectacular and amazing feats of daring in water that is over 6 feet deep!
Hello?
I don't quite know how to put this.
Benjamin?
Look, I was thinking about that time after the party...
Where are you?
And I was wondering if I could buy you a drink or something.
- Uh, the taft hotel - Did you get a room?
No.
Now, I know it's pretty late, and if you'd rather...
- Give me an hour. - What?
I'll be there in an hour.
It's in the main ballroom.
Over there.
Can I help you, sir?
What? Oh, no, I' m just...
Are you here for an affair, sir?
- What? - The singleman party, sir?
Oh, yes. The singleman party.
- It 's in the main ballroom. - Ahh. Thank you.
- Hello. - Hello.
- You must be one of the porters. - No, actually I' m not.
Yes. I' d like you to meet my sister, Miss Dewitte.
- How do you do? - How do you do Miss Dewitte?
And that's my husband Mr. Singleman.
- Oh, sorry. - That's Jeffrey, of course.
Of course. I didn't get your name, sir.
- Benjamin braddock, sir. - Braddock, braddock...
- Yes, but I' m afraid... - No, no no...
I'll find your table in just a moment.
Braddock. Braddock. Not braniff.
We have a Braniff.
No, actually, I'm just looking for a friend.
Well, I don't understand.
I'm not with your party. I'm sorry.
Hey, I don't get it.
I've enjoyed meeting you, Mr. Braniff.
- Hello Benjamin? - Oh, hello.
- May I sit down? - Of course.
Thank you.
- How are you? - Very well, thank you.
- May I have a drink? - A drink? Of course.
- He didn't see me. - Waiter.
- I will have a martini. - Yes, ma'am.
You don't have to be so nervous, you know.
Nervous?
Well, I am a bit nervous. I mean, it's pretty hard to be suave when you're...
- Did you get us a room? - What?
Have you gotten us a room yet?
I haven't, no.
Do you want to?
Well, I don't... I mean, I could.
Or we could just talk.
You want me to get it?
No, no, I' II get it.
- Do you want to get it now? - Now?
Yes.
Well, I don't know.
- Why don't you get it? - Why don't I get it?
Well, I will, then, if you'll excuse me.
Excuse me.
Yes, sir?
A room. I'd like a room, please.
A single room or a double room?
A single, just for myself, please.
Sign the register, please.
- Anything wrong, sir? - What? No, nothing.
Do you have any luggage, Mr. Gladstone?
Luggage? Yes, yes, I do.
- Where is it? - What?
Where is your luggage?
It's in the car. It's out there in the car.
Very good, sir. I'll have a porter bring it in.
Oh, no.
I mean, I' d...
I'd rather not go to all the trouble of bringing it all in.
I just have a toothbrush.
I can get it myself, if that's all right.
Of course.
I'll have a porter show you the room.
Oh, well, actually, I' d just as soon find it myself.
I just have the toothbrush to carry up.
I can handle it myself.
Whatever you say, sir.
Thank you.
- Mrs. Robinson? - Yes?
For you.
Thank you.
- Hello. - Mrs. Robinson?
- Yes? - It 's Benjamin.
Yes?
Benjamin Braddock.
Benjamin, where are you?
Can you look through the glass?
- Can you see me now? - Yes, I can.
- I got a single room. - That's fine.
But there's one thing...
The desk clerk seemed to be a little bit suspicious.
Now, I don't know what the policy...
- Do you want to go up first? - Yes, I think that would be good.
I'll be up in 5 minutes.
- Good-bye, then. - Benjamin.
Yes?
Isn't there something you want to tell me?
- Tell you? - Yes.
Well, I want you to know how much I appreciate this. Really.
- The number. - What?
The room number, Benjamin. I think you ought to tell me that.
You're absolutely right.
It's 568.
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
Well...
I'll see you later, Mrs. Robinson.
Check, please.
- I got it. - Hmm?
- I say I got it. - Sir?
The toothbrush. I got it, all right.
- Very good, sir. - Yes.
- Well, good night. - Good night, sir.
Hello, Benjamin.
Hello, Mrs. Robinson.
Well.
Benjamin...
Yes.
I'll get undressed now. Is that all right?
Sure.
Shall I... I mean, should I just stand here?
I mean, I don't know what you want me to do.
- Why don't you watch? - Oh, sure. Thank you.
- Will you bring me a hanger? - What?
- A hanger. - Oh, yes.
Wood?
What?
Wood or wire? They have both.
- Either one would be fine. - Ok.
Thank you.
Would you help me with this, please?
Certainly.
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
Benjamin, would this be easier for you in the dark?
Mrs. Robinson, I can't do this.
- You what? - This is all terribly wrong.
- Do you find me undesirable? - Oh, no, Mrs. Robinson.
I think you're the most attractive of all my parents' friends.
I mean that. I find you desirable, but I...
For god's sake, can you imagine my parents?
Can you imagine what they'd say if they just saw us here in this room right now?
- What would they say? - I have no idea, Mrs. Robinson,
but for god's sake.
They brought me up. They made a good life for me,
and I think they deserve better than this.
I think they deserve a little better than jumping into bed with the partner's wife.
Are you afraid of me?
Oh, no, you're missing the point. Look...
Maybe we could do something else together.
Mrs. Robinson, would you like to go to a movie?
Can I ask you a personal question?
- Ask me anything you want. - Is this your first time?
- Is this what? - It is, isn't it?
It is your first time.
That's a laugh, Mrs. Robinson. That's really a laugh.
- You can admit that, can't you? - Are you kidding?
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
- Wait a minute. - On your first time...
Who said it was my first time? Wait a minute.
Just because you happen to be inadequate.
Inadequate?
- Well, I guess I better... - Don't move!
Ben, what are you doing?
Well, I would say that I' m just drifting here in the pool
Why?
Well, it's very comfortable just to drift here.
Have you thought about graduate school
No.
Would you mind telling me what those 4 years of college were for?
What was the point of all that hard work?
You got me.
Now, listen, Ben...
Look.
I think it's a very good thing that a young man,
after he's done some very good work,
should have a chance to relax and enjoy himself
and lie around and drink beer and so on.
But after a few weeks,
I believe that person would want to take some stock in himself and his situation
and start to think about getting off his ass.
Robinsons are here.
Hi, Ben. What are you doing with yourself these days?
Oh, not too much.
Taking it easy.
That's what I' d do if I could. Nothing wrong with that.
Hey, Ben. Elaine's coming down from berkeley soon.
I want you to call her up this time.
I will.
Because I just think you two would hit it off real well together.
Say hello to Mrs. Robinson, Benjamin.
Hello, Mrs. Robinson.
Hello, Benjamin.
- Oh, my. - Hi.
- Hi. Can I talk to you for a minute? - Sure.
Benjy...
Darling, I' m going to ask you something, but you...
You don't have to tell me if you don't want to.
What?
Well, I' m going to ask you what you do when you go off at night.
When I go off?
You don't have to tell me if you don't want to.
No, I do. I want to tell you.
I drive around.
- What else? - Nothing else.
You don't drive around from midnight until noon the next day, Benjamin.
Oh, no.
Well, then, what do you do?
You meet someone?
Meet someone?
- Why do you say that? - Well, this is your business.
- I won't play games with you. - Wait, wait.
I don't meet anyone, mother, but why do you say that?
Benjamin, I don't want to pry into your affairs,
but I would rather you didn't say anything at all than be dishonest.
- Good night. - Well, wait...
Wait a minute!
Will you wait a minute, please?
Mrs. Robinson, do you think we could say a few words to each other first this time?
I don't think we have much to say to each other.
Look, for months, all we've done is come up here and leap into bed together.
Are you tired of it?
I'm not, no.
But do you think we could liven it up with a little conversation for a change?
What do you want to talk about?
Anything. Anything at all.
Do you want to tell me about some of your college experiences?
Oh, my god.
Think of another topic.
How about art?
Art. That's a good subject.
You start it off.
You start it off. I don't know anything about it.
Well, what do you want to know about it?
Are you interested more in modern art or in classical art?
Neither.
- You're not interested in art? - No.
Then why do you want to talk about it?
I don't.
Now, look, we're going to do this thing. We're going to have a conversation.
Tell me what you did today.
I got up.
- I fixed breakfast for my husband. - There.
There's something we could have a conversation about... your husband.
Oh. Him.
I mean, everything.
I don't know anything about how you work this.
What do you say to him when you leave the house at night?
Nothing. He's asleep.
Always?
Doesn't he wake up when you come home?
We have separate bedrooms.
Oh, I see.
So you don't...
I don't like to seem like I' m prying, but I guess you don't sleep together.
No, we don't.
How long has this been going on?
- For god's sake, let's drop this. - Wait a minute.
Why did you marry him?
See if you can guess.
Well, I can't.
Think real hard, Benjamin.
I can't see why you did, unless...
You didn't have to marry him or anything, did you?
Don't tell Elaine.
Oh, no. You had to marry him because you got pregnant.
Are you shocked?
I never thought of you and Mr. Robinson as the kind of people who...
All right now, let's get to bed.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
So how did it happen?
- What? - You and Mr. Robinson.
Do you feel like telling me what were the circumstances?
Not particularly.
- Was he a law student at the time? - Mm-hmm.
- And you were a student also? - Mm-hmm.
At college?
Yes.
What was your major?
Benjamin, why are you asking me all these questions?
Because I' m interested, Mrs. Robinson.
What was your major subject at college?
- Art. - Art?
But I thought you...
I guess you kind of lost interest in it over the years, then.
Kind of.
Well, how did it happen?
- What? - You and Mr. Robinson.
How do you think?
Did you take you up to his room with him?
Did you go to a hotel
Oh, Benjamin, what does it possibly matter?
I'm curious.
- We'd go to his car. - Oh, no.
In the car you did it?
Well, I don't think we were the first.
What kind of car was it?
What?
Do you remember the make of the car?
- Oh, my god. - Really, I want to know.
It was a ford, Benjamin.
A ford.
A ford. God damn it, that's great. A ford.
That's enough.
So old Elaine Robinson got started in a ford.
Don't talk about Elaine.
Don't talk about Elaine?
No.
Why not?
Because I don't want you to.
Well, why don't you?
I wish you'd tell me.
There's nothing to tell.
Well, why is she a big taboo subject all of a sudden?
Well, I guess I' II have to ask her out on a date and find out what the big deal is.
Benjamin, don't you ever take that girl out.
Do you understand that?
I have no intention of taking her out.
Good.
I was just kidding around.
Well, why shouldn't I
- I have my reasons. - Then let's hear them.
No.
Let's hear them, Mrs. Robinson, because I think I know what they are.
I'm not good enough for her to associate with, am I
I'm not good enough to even talk about her, am I
- Let's drop it. - We're not dropping it.
I'm good enough for you, but I' m not good enough to associate with your daughter.
- That's it, isn't it? - Benjamin.
Isn't it?
Yes.
You go to hell. You go straight to hell, Mrs. Robinson.
Do you think I' m proud of myself?
- Do you think I' m proud of this? - I wouldn't know.
Well, I am not.
No, sir.
I'm not proud that I spend my time with a broken-down alcoholic.
I see.
If you think I come here for any reason besides pure boredom than you're all wrong.
'Cause, Mrs. Robinson,
this is the sickest, most perverted thing that ever happened to me.
You do what you want, but I' m getting the hell out.
Are you?
Goddamn right, I am.
That's how you feel about me? That I' m a sick and disgusting person?
- Now, don't start this. - What?
Don't start acting hurt.
Don't you expect me to be a little hurt?
Mrs. Robinson, you lie there and tell me I'm not good enough for your daughter.
Did I say that?
In so many words.
Benjamin, I want to apologize to you if that's the impression you got.
Well, 2 minutes ago you told me I wasn't good enough for your daughter.
Now you say you're sorry I got that impression.
I didn't mean it.
I don't think you'd be right for each other.
I'd never say you aren't as good a person as she is.
You wouldn't?
Of course I wouldn't.
What are you doing?
Well, it's pretty obvious you don't want me around anymore.
Well, look, uh...
I was kind of upset there.
I'm sorry I said those things.
It's all right.
I think I can understand why I' m disgusting to you.
Oh, no.
Look, I like you. I wouldn't keep coming here if I didn't like you.
But if it's sickening for you?
It's not.
I enjoy it. I look forward to it. It 's the one thing I have to look forward to.
You don't have to say that.
Well, I wouldn't.
I would never say it if it wasn't true.
May I stay, then?
Yes, please. I want you to.
- Thank you. - Well, don't.
Thank me, because I want you to.
But you won't ever take Elaine out, will you?
I want you to promise me that.
Look, why the hell did you bring this up?
It never occurred to me to take her out.
Then give me your word you won't!
This is absurd.
Promise me, Benjamin.
All right, I promise.
For christ's sake, I promise I'll never take out Elaine Robinson.
Thank you.
- Benjamin... - Let's not talk about it.
Let's not talk at all.
Elaine's back home soon.
I think it might be a nice gesture if you asked her out.
I suppose she's not good enough for you, is that it?
Look, Elaine Robinson and I do not get along.
How do you know? You haven't seen her since high school
I suppose your evenings,
whatever you do with them, are just too valuable.
That has nothing to do with it.
I guess I' II just have to tell Mr. Robinson...
that you're too busy every evening doing god knows what.
Now don't go on like this.
If Benjamin absolutely refuses to take her out...
I do.
Then I will simply have to invite all the Robinsons over on Thursday.
Well, Braddock, it's about time you got around to this.
Your wife predicted you would say what?
No points. Right?
Here's the next question. Gentlemen...
Hello.
What is your wife's most unusual habit?
Ben, come on in.
I'm afraid the young lady isn't quite ready yet.
What would you say to a short one?
- Scotch still your drink? - Bourbon.
Can you think of something that bothers you?
Not shaving her legs.
Well, I' II see if she's ready.
Listen, this was not my idea. This was my father's idea.
Benjamin, I thought I made myself perfectly clear about this.
Look, we'll go out to dinner and have a drink, and I' II bring her right back.
Because it was either that or a dinner party for the 2 families.
And I' m afraid I couldn't quite handle that, if you don't mind.
Look, I have no intention of ever taking your precious daughter out again,
- so don't get upset about it. - I am.
I'm extremely upset about it, Benjamin.
Hello.
I want you to keep your wits about you tonight.
You never know what tricks Ben picked up back there in the east.
You're living at home now, is that right?
Yes.
Do you know what you're going to do?
No.
Are you going to graduate school
Do you always drive like this?
Yes.
Sit down.
Why don't you watch the show?
Benjamin, do you dislike me for some reason?
No. Why should I
I don't know.
You're missing a great effect here.
How do you like that?
Could you do it?
Go, baby, go!
- Stop! - Hey!
Elaine, I' m sorry.
Elaine.
Would you take me home now?
I'm sorry I took you in there.
I think I better go home, please.
Elaine.
Where's the car?
I just want to tell you something.
I want to go home.
But, I just tell you this one thing?
What?
This whole idea... this date and everything, it was my parents' idea.
They forced me into it.
That's very nice of you to tell me.
No, what I mean is, that's why I' ve been acting this way.
I'm not like this. I hate myself like this.
Listen, could you just stop crying, please?
No, I couldn't.
- Well, could you try? - No.
I've had his feeling ever since I' ve graduated...
This kind of compulsion that I have to be rude all the time,
You know what I mean?
Yes, I do.
It's like I was playing some kind of game,
but the rules don't make any sense to me.
They're being made up by all the wrong people.
No.
I mean, no one makes them up. They seem to make themselves up.
Say!
Could I request that you turn that down?
Would you like to come in?
I could make you some coffee.
No. I wouldn't want to wake anyone up.
We won't.
Let's go inside.
Wait a minute.
Is anything wrong?
No. I was just thinking.
It's still early.
Maybe we could do something, go somewhere else.
All right.
Where are we going?
I'm trying to think of... where there's a place to have a drink around here.
Isn't there one at the taft hotel
What is the matter?
Nothing. I' m just wondering if they have a bar or not.
I mean, let's go see.
Let's go see if they do or not.
Listen, Elaine, it seems to me that there isn't a bar here.
I mean, as far as I know.
Of course there is. Look, there's the palm room right there.
Good evening.
- Hello. - How are you, sir?
Good evening, Mr. Gladstone.
Hello again.
Hi, Mr. Gladstone. How are you this evening?
Benjamin?
Let's get out of here, Elaine. Let's go somewhere else.
- Do they know you? - Of course not.
- Good evening, sir. - Come on, Elaine, we're leaving.
Mr. Gladstone, how are you?
- Benjamin, what's happening? - I don't know.
They must think I look like this guy Gladstone.
Hello, Mr. Braniff.
Elaine, I like you. Ilike you so much.
Do you believe that?
- Do you? - Yes.
You're the first...
You're the first thing for so long that I' ve liked,
the first person I could stand to be with.
My whole life is such a waste.
It's just nothing.
I'm sorry. I'll take you home now.
Benjamin, are you having an affair with someone?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. That's not my business.
It just happened.
It's just this thing that happened along with everything else.
Can you understand that?
Was she married or something?
Yes.
With a family?
Yes. She had a husband and a son.
- Did they ever find out? - No.
And it's all over now?
Yes.
I'm glad.
Can we do something tomorrow?
All right.
During the day we'll go for a drive or something.
Ok.
- You sure you really want to? - Yes.
Because I wouldn't want you to do it unless you really wanted to.
I do.
You do?
- Benjamin, I really do. - Shh!
Drive down the block.
Mrs. Robinson,
Elaine and I have a date. We're going for a drive.
Do exactly as I say.
- Now it seems to me... - Listen to me very carefully, Benjamin.
You are not to see Elaine again ever.
Those are my orders. Is that clear?
Mrs. Robinson, do you think...
I can make things quite unpleasant.
How?
In order to keep Elaine away from you, I' m prepared to tell her everything.
I don't believe you.
Then you'd better start believing me.
I just don't believe you would do that.
Try me.
God damn it.
Elaine! Elaine!
- Benjamin. - I' m coming up!
I'm not dressed yet.
Benjamin, I said I wasn't dressed.
You've got to go over the back fence, and I' II meet you on the corner.
- What's the matter? - Hurry. Put your shoes on.
Benjamin.
- Benjamin, what are you doing? - Elaine...
- Elaine, I have to tell you something. - What is it?
- That woman... - Woman?
The woman that older woman that I told you about...
- You mean that one? - Yes. The married woman.
- That wasn't just some woman. - What are you telling me?
Benjamin, would you just tell me what this is about?
- Oh, no. - Elaine.
- Oh, my god. - Please.
- Get out of here. - Don't cry.
Get out! Get out!
Out! Get out!
Good-bye, Benjamin.
Say that again?
I'm going to marry Elaine Robinson.
- Well, well, well! - What's happening?
Ben says that he and Elaine are getting married.
I don't believe it.
- That's what he says, Right? - I' m going up to berkeley today.
Oh, Ben, It 's so exciting!
Come on. We've got to call the Robinsons.
We've got something to celebrate.
No. I think you'll want to wait on that.
- Oh, they don't know? - No, they don't.
- When did you decide all this? - About an hour ago.
Wait a minute. You talked to Elaine this morning?
No. She doesn't know about it.
You mean she doesn't know that you're coming up to berkeley?
No. Actually, she doesn't know about us getting married yet.
Well, when did you two talk this over?
- We haven't. - You haven't?
Ben, this whole idea sounds pretty half -baked.
No, it's not. It's completely baked.
It's a decision I' ve made.
Well, what makes you think she wants to marry you?
She doesn't. To be perfectly honest, she doesn't like me.
- You a student? What's that? - Not exactly.
I said not exactly, no.
What are you then?
I'm just sort of traveling through.
Ilike to know who's living in my house.
Ilike to know what my boys are up to.
I'm not up to much actually.
I'm just visiting.
I mean, I' ve always wanted to see berkeley.
- You're not one of those agitators? - What?
- One of those outside agitators? - Oh, no.
I hate that. I won't stand for it.
I won't stand for that.
Pardon me.
Well, how about this for a coincidence?
I was wondering where you were headed.
I'm meeting someone.
Where?
Where are you meeting this person?
At the zoo.
The zoo.
They have a pretty good one here, do they?
I don't know. I've never seen it.
Well, I haven't, either.
I might just ride out there with you.
- Is that him over there? - No.
Where did he say he was going to meet you?
I thought he said by the monkey house.
Benjamin, I would like to know what you're doing here.
- Here? In berkeley? - Yes.
Well, I have this very pleasant room, and I' ve been getting into some classes.
- But you're not enrolled. - No, I just sit in.
They don't seem to mind. They've been very congenial about it.
Benjamin, you're... I don't know what to say.
Maybe we can get together sometime and talk about it.
Really incredible.
- Here he comes. - What?
I got a real feeling that this is the fella.
Elaine!
He certainly is a good walker.
Am I late? I' m sorry.
We thought you said by the monkey house.
This is Benjamin Braddock. Carl smith.
Benjamin rode here with me on the bus.
- Glad to meet you, Ben. - Great meeting you, Carl
Swell seeing you.
Who is it?
I want to ask you a question, and then I' m going.
- Come in. - No.
I want to know why you're here in berkeley.
Because... I am.
Is it because I' m here?
- What do you think? - I think it is.
- I said I think it is. - All right, then. Yes.
- Well, I want you to leave. - Well, look, I love you.
How could you do that, Benjamin? Do you just hate Everything?
How could you possibly rape my mother?
- What? - I don't understand...
- Did you say Rape her? - I don't understand how anyone...
What did she say? Tell me what she said.
- Why? - Because it isn't true.
Tell me.
She said that she was having a drink at the hotel with a friend,
and that you waited for her in the parking lot and told her that...
she was too drunk to drive home and that you would get her a room for the night.
Oh, then what?
Then you took her upstairs, and you raped her.
Oh, no, no. That's not what happened.
What happened was there was this party at my parents'.
- I drove your mother home... - I don't want to hear this!
- We went upstairs to see your portrait... - No! I don't!
- She started taking her clothes off, - This is my mother, Benjamin!
And suddenly, there she was without any clothes on... I mean, really naked.
Oh, shut... aah!
- Oh, hello, Mr. Mccleery. - Who screamed?
It's all right, Mr. Mccleery.
Screaming is not all right, not in my house, It isn't.
It was just a visitor, but it's all right now.
What did you do to her?
Look, she's all right. She's upset, and she screamed, but it's ok now.
- Shall I get the cops? - What?
- I' II get the cops. - Hey, wait a minute.
Now, damn it, look.
Here she is, having some water.
There's no need for the cops or anything.
All right, boys, you can all go back to your rooms now.
Go ahead.
We won't have any more of this agitation.
- Will we, Braddock? - No, sir.
I want you out of here.
- What do you mean? - You heard me out of here.
- What for? - Because I don't like you.
I'm sorry I screamed.
Benjamin, when you came up here,
what did you think was going to happen between us?
Elaine, right now I don't feel like talking much.
I'm sorry about everything, but I think I' II just do this now.
Can I just sit here while you're packing?
What are you going to do now?
I don't know.
- Are you going home? - No.
Well, where are you going?
Elaine, you're going to have to stop asking me that.
I don't want you to leave tomorrow.
I don't understand.
I don't want you to go anywhere...
Until you have a definite plan.
Good-bye.
What's happening?
- Benjamin? - What?
Will you kiss me?
Will you marry me?
- You won't? - I don't know.
But you might?
I might.
Is that so?
- You might marry me? - Yes.
When?
I don't know.
How about tomorrow? I don't mean to be pushy.
I don't know what's happening.
You mean you're confused?
Look, don't be confused.
We're getting married.
I don't see how we can.
We just can.
I have to go now.
Hey, Elaine?
Are you serious about this?
I'll think about it.
- You really will? - Yes.
Good god.
We can go get our blood tests tomorrow.
- Tomorrow? - Or this afternoon.
It's a good day for it.
Benjamin, I haven't even said I' II marry you yet.
We'll need our birth certificates.
I happen to have mine with me. Where's yours?
- I just don't think it would work. - Why wouldn't it?
- Why wouldn't it? - I just don't think it would.
Tomorrow, then. Can we get our blood tests tomorrow morning?
Why don't you just drag me off if you want to marry me so much?
Why don't I just drag you off?
All right. I will, right after we get the blood tests.
I have to see Carl first.
Carl who?
Carl smith. He's a medical student. We've known him for years.
- Who, that guy at the zoo? - Yes.
- Why do you have to see him? - Well, I said I might marry him.
You what?!
How did he do it?
Did he get down on his knees?
He didn't get down on his knees, I hope.
No, Benjamin.
What did he say? I'm curious.
Shh.
He said he thought we'd make a pretty good team.
- Oh, no. He said that? - Shh!
Where did he do it?
I'd like to know where it happened.
It wasn't in his car, was it?
Good night.
Are we getting married tomorrow?
No.
The day after tomorrow?
I don't know. Maybe we are, and maybe we're not.
Do you want to, uh... do you want to try and tell me why you did it?
Mr. Robinson.
Do you have a special grudge against me?
Do you feel a particularly strong resentment?
No.
Is there something I' ve said that's caused this contempt,
or is it just things I stand for that you despise?
It was nothing to do with you, sir.
Well, Ben, it was quite a bit to do with me.
Now, look, please...
Ben, I think we're 2 civilized human beings.
Do you think it's necessary to threaten each other?
I'm not threatening you.
Do you want to unclench your fist, please? Thank you.
I can see in the dark, you know. I've been here quite a while.
I'm trying to tell you I have no personal feelings about you, Mr. Robinson.
I'm trying to tell you I do not resent you.
You don't respect me terribly much, either.
- No, sir. - What?
- No, sir. - Don't shout at me, Ben.
I may not be as young as you, but I still have pretty good hearing.
- Mr. Robinson... - Have the decency to wait until I finish.
I do think you should know the consequences of what you've done.
I do think you should know that my wife and I are getting a divorce soon.
But why?
Why?!
Listen to me.
What happened between Mrs. Robinson and me was nothing.
It didn't mean anything.
We might just as well have been shaking hands.
Shaking hands.
That's not saying much for my wife, is it?
- You miss the point. - I guess I do.
The point is, I don't love your wife. Ilove your daughter, sir.
All right. Now listen to this.
I don't know whether I can prosecute, but I think I can.
I think I can get you behind bars if you ever look at my daughter again.
I've seen Elaine, and I' ve made damn sure you can't get to her.
Stay away from me, Ben!
I don't want to mince words with you.
As far as Elaine is concerned, you're to get her out of your filthy mind right now.
Is that perfectly clear to you?
And that's all, Ben. You'll pardon me if I don't shake hands with you.
I think you are filth.
I think you are scum!
You are a degenerate!
Hi.
Mr. Mccleery, do you have some change? I need to use the phone.
I want you out of here.
Look, I' II give you $10 for a dime. I'll give you 20.
For god's sake, will you let me use that phone?
I'm going to call the police... now.
Could I make one phone call first?
Get out of here!
Elaine Robinson has left school
Her roommate's coming down with a note for you.
Dear Benjamin, please forgive me,
because I know what I' m doing is the best thing for you.
My father is so upset. You've got to understand.
Ilove you, but it would never work out.
Elaine?
Hello, Benjamin.
Where is she?
- Hello. Get me the police, please. - Where's Elaine?
I'll be with you in a moment, Benjamin.
Do you have a patrol car in the vicinity of 1200 glenview road?
Good. We have a burglar here.
Just a second. I' II ask him. Are you armed?
No, I don't believe he is.
Thank you.
What have you done to her?
I think we have everything quite under control now, Benjamin.
Would you like a quick drink before you go?
You can't stop me from seeing her. I'll find her.
Sorry we won't be able to invite you to the wedding Benjamin,
but the arrangements have been so rushed.
What the hell have you...
I don't think you'll have time for that drink after all.
- I' II find her. - I don't think so.
Say, fellas.
Do any of you fellas know where carl smith is?
He took off in the middle of the night to get married.
Probably one step ahead of the shotgun.
Would you happen to know where he's getting married?
I'm supposed to be there.
Why don't you ask Carter?
Would you happen to know where I might find him?
Hey, Carter!
Where's the make-out king getting married?
Santa barbara!
You don't happen to know exactly...
where the old make-out king is getting married, do you?
I'm supposed to be there.
Where in santa barbara?
I don't know. Maybe his old man's house, or in the maternity ward.
- Hey, you going to the wedding? - Yeah.
Hey, tell him to save a piece for me.
Of the wedding cake!
- Can I use your phone? - Yeah.
Hello, who is this?
This is Dr. Smith's answering service.
Is the doctor anywhere?
I'm afraid the doctor can't be reached right now. If you'd like to leave...
I have to know where he is.
Well, the doctor is at his son's wedding, but I' m sure it's over by now.
He should be checking in at any moment.
Listen to me. I'm Dr. Smith's brother,
reverend smith, and I' m supposed to perform the ceremony.
I just got in from Portland, and I' ve forgotten what church, you see?
Well, I' m not sure, but you might try the first presbyterian. That's on allan street.
Thank you.
Allan street, where is it?
Uh, allan, uh... It's, uh... it's uh...
It's 6 blocks up and, uh, 3 over.
You need any gas, father?
Oh, Jesus god. No.
Elaine!
Who is that guy? What's he doing?
- I' II take care of him. - He's too late.
Elaine!
Elaine! Elaine!
We've got to stop him!
Ben!
You punk. You crazy punk!
I'll kill you.
Elaine! It 's too late!
Not for me!
- Move! Move! - Damn you!